Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications records, 1971-1997 and undated RL.11370
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications records
1971-1997 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11370
18.2 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Brouillard Communications, a division of JWT, was established in 1973 and specialized in business-to-business advertising and corporate communications. Brouillard closed in 2009. Collection includes correspondence and other printed materials, proofs and tear sheets, slides and videocassettes. Companies represented include Eaton, Irving Trust, Mellon Bank, New York Stock Exchange and Transamerica. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.ing and corporate communications. Brouillard closed in 2009. Collection iIncludes correspondence and other printed materials, proofs and tear sheets, slides and videocassettes. Companies represented include Eaton, Irving Trust, Mellon Bank, New York Stock Exchange and Transamerica. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged into three series: General Files; Slides; Audiovisual Materials.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Brouillard Communications records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2004.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center Collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files; J. Walter Thompson Company Corporate Documentation; J. Walter Thompson Company Domestic Advertisements; J. Walter Thompson Company Iconographic Collection; J. Walter Thompson Company New Business records.
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence and other printed materials, proofs and tear sheets, slides and videocassettes. Companies represented include Eaton, Irving Trust, Mellon Bank, New York Stock Exchange and Transamerica. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Eaton Corporation; Irving Trust Company; New York Stock Exchange
- General Files, 1971-1989; undated; 1
  - Brouillard in brief, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Credentials binder, 1989; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Eaton creative, undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Eaton print advertisements, 1976; undated (Box 1)
  - Eaton, Irving Trust, Mellon Bank creative, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Foster, "Winning II" presentation, 1986-1986 (Box 1)
  - Information packet, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Jacques Bouchard, L'Autre Publicite, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Mellon Bank transcripts, undated (Box 1)
  - Pittsburgh "Man in the Street" interview project, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - RCA print advertisements, undated (Box 2)
  - Selling from the corporate point of view, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Textron print advertisements, 1971; undated (Box 2)
  - The corporate need to communicate, 1970s (Box 10)
  - Transamerica, 1986 (Box 2)
  - What is a Company? Philadelphia, 1985 (Box 2)
  - What's new from the corporate point of view, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Winning!, 1986 (Box 10)
- Slides, approximately 1970s-1980s; 2
  - Ads with space theme (Box 2)
  - Advertising presentation (Box 2)
  - AGA, Amex (Box 2)
  - Atlantic Mutual (Box 2)
  - Australian Meat (Box 2)
  - Banking and general ads (Box 2)
  - Blue Cross/Blue Shield New York (Box 2)
  - Case histories A-Z, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Case histories A-Z, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Chemical Bank (Box 3)
  - Chemical, pharmaceutical ads (Box 3)
  - CMA (Box 3)
  - Corporate advertising, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Corporate advertising, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - DDB (Box 4)
  - Eaton (Box 4)
  - FDU corporate advertising overview, Tom Garbett, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Financial ads, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Foreign ads, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Foster, "Winning II" presentation, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - FSA (Box 5)
  - General ads, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - General advertising presentations (Box 5)
  - Goodyear (Box 5)
  - Goodyear, Glaxo (Box 5)
  - Goodyear management presentation (Box 5)
  - GTE (Box 5)
  - Insurance (Box 5)
  - Irving Trust (Box 5)
  - Issue (Box 5)
  - Marketing approach to corporate/outdoor advertising (Box 5)
  - Marsh & McLennan (Box 5)
  - MBIA (Box 5)
  - Mellon Bank (Box 5)
  - Midcon (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z, 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Modular slide presentations, Jim Foster, 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Modular titles, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Name change, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) (Box 7)
  - Original name change (Box 7)
  - Presentations (Box 7)
  - Prince (Box 7)
  - Random ads, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Recession, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Salvation Army (Box 7)
  - Signal (Box 7)
  - Sonat (Box 7)
  - Standard spare ads, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - TAB (Box 8)
  - TELCO (Box 8)
  - Telephone compannies, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Time Magazine presentation (Box 8)
  - Titles: Cartoons, elephants (Box 8)
  - Tom Garbett, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - United Way (Box 8)
  - Untitled binder, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Untitled binder, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Unum (Box 9)
  - World War II, 1930s-1950s (Box 9)
  - Various metal slides (box) (Box 9)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1982-1997; undated; 3
  - BBDO--DuPont Corporate spots, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-001)
    Scope and Contents
    Bill Demby; Mary Brodie; Hot Work; Applause
  - Chiat/Day--Drexel Burhnam spots, 1988 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-002)
    Playground; Vidalia; Kindercare; Sign
  - DDB Needham--Corporate Advertising Commercials (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-003)
    Prepared for ANA Corporate Advertising Workshop, Thomas Garbett
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--Corporate Campaigns, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-004)
    G. Glassman: Champion; Boeing; Johnson Controls
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--Kaleidescope, 1982 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-005)
    ANA Corporate Workshop, Thomas Garbett
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--Overview of Corporate Advertising, 1982 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-006)
    Prepared for ANA, Thomas Garbett
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--TV Commercials, 1983 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-007)
    Thomas Garbett, edited version of Kaleidescope
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach--Thomas Garbett Kaleidescope edit TV Commercials, 1983 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-008)
  - Geer, DuBois--BASF "Spirit", 1988 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-009)
  - General Motors, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-010)
    Prologue; Quality of Worklife; New Engine; Auburn Hills; 10 Cars; Safety; New Methods; Epilogue; Kennedy Center Closing Billboards
  - J. Walter Thompson--Assorted Commercials, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-011)
  - J. Walter Thompson--British Airways, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-012)
  - J. Walter Thompson--Corporate Advertising, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-013)
    Coca-Cola; General Electric; IBM; Dow; DuPont; Xerox
  - J. Walter Thompson--Corporate Spots, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-014)
    NEC; DuPont; General Electric; BASF; Chevron; ADM; PM; IBM; Xerox; Dow
  - J. Walter Thompson--Drexel Burnham, Undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-015)
  - J. Walter Thompson--Long Running Campaigns I, Undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-016)
  - J. Walter Thompson--Reference Reel, Corporate Advertising, 1994 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-017)
    ADM; International Paper; TRW; Microsoft
  - Mellon/Westinghouse/Heinz/PPG, 1985 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-018)
  - Original spots, Undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-019)
  - Pittsburgh interviews edit 2, 1985 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-020)
  - Public Service Announcements (J. Walter Thompson Company), 1992 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-021)
  - Radio TV Reports--Arthur Anderson; Drexel Burhnam, 1988 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-022)
  - Southwestern Bell "Together" spots, 1984 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-023)
  - Wall Street Journal Perspectives on Corporate Advertising: Thomas Garbett, Doyle Dane Bernbach, 1982 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-024)
  - Who's a Company?--3M; General Electric II, 1988 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-025)
  - Who's a Company?--Allied Signal; ARCO; Bank of New York; Chase Manhattan; NCR; Ryder; Union Carbide, 1988 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-026)
  - Who's a Company?--Bay Bank, Malcolm intro and ending, 1993 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-027)
  - Who's a Company?--Campbell Soup; Westinghouse; Exxon; Avon; Kellogg's, 1996 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-028)
  - Who's a Company?--Kodak; Xerox; 3M I, 1988 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-029)
  - Who's a Company?--Kodak; Xerox; 3M; General Electric, 1988 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-030)
  - Who's a Company?--Kodak; Xerox; 3M; General Electric, 1988 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-031)
  - Who's a Company?--Kodak; Xerox; 3M; General Electric, 1988 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-032)
  - Who's a Company?--Pittsburgh 1, 1984 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-033)
  - Who's a Company?--Pittsburgh 2, 1984 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-034)
  - Who's a Company?--Pittsburgh 3, 1984 (Box AV3, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-035)
  - Who's a Company?--Philadelphia, 1985 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11370-UMATIC-036)
  - BBDO South--American Forest Council: Bear; Woodpecker, 1991 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11370-VHS-001)
  - DMB&B--Dow Chemical 14 spots, 1989 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11370-VHS-002)
  - Farley Industries spots, 1987 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11370-VHS-003)
  - Michael Beckman Associates--Storm over the Seas, 1992 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11370-VHS-004)
  - Who's a Company?--AMEX, 1997 (Box AV4, Video-cassette RL11370-VHS-005)